<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>atom on ITOHI</title><link>https://itohi.com/tags/atom/</link><description>Recent content in atom on ITOHI</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><copyright>2022 @ ITOHI - All rights reserved</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2019 01:01:28 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://itohi.com/tags/atom/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Arduino ESP8266 Smart Motion Sensor using PIR and MQTT</title><link>https://itohi.com/esp-motion/esp-1-smart-motion-sensor-using-pir-and-mqtt/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2019 01:01:28 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://itohi.com/esp-motion/esp-1-smart-motion-sensor-using-pir-and-mqtt/</guid><description>
My son has a cat. And I've become very curious about the cat's feeding and toilet habits. Mainly I'm interested in how long does it take him to go to the toilet after eating as I've noticed a pattern: At first he goes to the kitchen, eats and then runs around the house wrecking havoc for some time and then goes to the toilet. So I'm curious whether this is his usual routine and moreover how many times during the day and night does he need to use his toilet.</description></item><item><title>Arduino ESP8266 Smart Motion Sensor using PIR and MQTT (compat)</title><link>https://itohi.com/blog/esp-1-smart-motion-sensor-using-pir-and-mqtt/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2019 01:01:28 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://itohi.com/blog/esp-1-smart-motion-sensor-using-pir-and-mqtt/</guid><description>
The purpose of this post is to not upset the existing links to this post. The actual post moved to /esp-motion/esp-1-smart-motion-sensor-using-pir-and-mqtt/.</description></item><item><title>Arduino Developing with Atom IDE and PlatformIO for AVR and ESP chips</title><link>https://itohi.com/blog/developing-with-atom-ide-and-platformio/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Jul 2018 01:01:28 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://itohi.com/blog/developing-with-atom-ide-and-platformio/</guid><description>
There are many different ways to develop and deploy embedded solutions, one of the most popular ones would be Arduino IDE. But the editor is very simplistic, without handy features such as intellisense, code refactoring and many others. I've used AVR Studio, IAR, even VIM to develop code for AVR/STM microcontrollers.. But they are either designed specifically for that platform or are commercial products. And I love Open Source :)</description></item></channel></rss>