<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>IoT on ITOHI</title><link>https://itohio.github.io/tags/iot/</link><description>Recent content in IoT on ITOHI</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><copyright>2022 @ ITOHI - All rights reserved</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2019 01:01:28 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://itohio.github.io/tags/iot/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Arduino ESP8266 Smart Motion Sensor using PIR and MQTT</title><link>https://itohio.github.io/blog/esp-1-smart-motion-sensor-using-pir-and-mqtt/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2019 01:01:28 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://itohio.github.io/blog/esp-1-smart-motion-sensor-using-pir-and-mqtt/</guid><description>
Motivation My son has a cat. And I've become very curious about the cat's feeding and toilet habits. Mainly I'm interested in how long does it take him to go to the toilet after eating as I've noticed a pattern: At first he goes to the kitchen, eats and then runs around the house wrecking havoc for some time and then goes to the toilet. So I'm curious whether this is his usual routine and moreover how many times during the day and night does he need to use his toilet.</description></item><item><title>Building ESP8266 Weather station with BME280 (part 2)</title><link>https://itohio.github.io/blog/building-esp8266-weather-station-part-ii/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2019 01:01:28 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://itohio.github.io/blog/building-esp8266-weather-station-part-ii/</guid><description>
In a previous post I've described how to build a Weather Station based on ESP8266 chip and various breakout boards you can buy e.g. on Aliexpress. In this post, however I'll share with you how I built a standalone PCB boards containing all the required components. To recap - this is a ESP8266 based Weather Station, that measures surrounding air temperature, humidity, pressure along with light and battery voltage. Connects to an MQTT broker and reports it's data there.</description></item><item><title>Building ESP8266 Weather station with BME280 (part 1)</title><link>https://itohio.github.io/blog/building-esp8266-weather-station-part-i/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Jul 2018 01:01:28 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://itohio.github.io/blog/building-esp8266-weather-station-part-i/</guid><description>
Ever since I started playing around with ESP modules I wanted to measure weather conditions in multiple location at home, friends, etc. The best way to achieve that would be to build a station that gathers various environment parameters and publishes them somewhere. That is what I've done. The very first prototype was done using ESP-1 module, DHT-11 humidity sensor and BMP280 breakout board. The station publishes gathered data to a MQTT broker from where it can be further gathered and analysed.</description></item></channel></rss>