<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Blogs on ITOHI</title><link>https://itohi.com/blog/</link><description>Recent content in Blogs on ITOHI</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><copyright>2022 @ ITOHI - All rights reserved</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 05 Dec 2022 20:05:19 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://itohi.com/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Adventures with Hugo</title><link>https://itohi.com/blog/adventures-with-hugo/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Dec 2022 20:05:19 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://itohi.com/blog/adventures-with-hugo/</guid><description>
I've been involved in Full Stack for a while now in one form or another(either maintaining, designing or working on Full Stack projects). Even during school time, I was building websites for myself and my friends. I've built sites commercially even. Although I've been using either pure HTML+JS or even PHP/Perl at some point. I rarely liked this activity, especially since the visual designs of the web pages were lacking and I just couldn't make myself study some visual design :(</description></item><item><title>How Its Been in 2020-2022</title><link>https://itohi.com/blog/how-its-been-in-2020-2022/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Nov 2022 12:46:27 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://itohi.com/blog/how-its-been-in-2020-2022/</guid><description>
Years 2020, 2021 and 2022 have been tough for almost everyone. The pandemic, the war, global economic collapse, bancruptcies in Crypto sphere... You name it. Although, for me it was a rather productive period(despite a divorce spanning almost 3 years), since I have accustomed to working from home and working on various project remotely. The range of projects varied from working on a system that tailors advertisements to people behavior to optimizing Internet traffic by cleverly and autonomously arranging relay nodes all around the globe.</description></item><item><title>Multilanguage Test</title><link>https://itohi.com/blog/multilanguage-test/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 May 2022 18:26:47 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://itohi.com/blog/multilanguage-test/</guid><description>
This is a simple test for multilanguage support. Sometimes I feel like writing in native tongue, sometimes in multiple languages... So, let's see how that goes.
Here's a comic strip about why I have so many unfinished projects:</description></item><item><title>Arduino Metal Detector using frequency counter and OLED display</title><link>https://itohi.com/blog/metal-detector-using-frequency-counter-and-oled-display/</link><pubDate>Sun, 08 Jul 2018 01:01:28 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://itohi.com/blog/metal-detector-using-frequency-counter-and-oled-display/</guid><description>
There are a lot of forests in Lithuania which I like exploring on my bike. In the past a lot of Lithuanian resistance troops resided in those forests, so there is a big probability to stumble upon a stash of some kind. However that stash might as well be a grenade or a bomb of some kind, but nevertheless I always wanted to combine my motorcycle riding through the woods with treasure hunting and some time ago I decided to build a simple metal detector.</description></item><item><title>Arduino Developing with Atom IDE and PlatformIO for AVR and ESP chips</title><link>https://itohi.com/blog/developing-with-atom-ide-and-platformio/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Jul 2018 01:01:28 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://itohi.com/blog/developing-with-atom-ide-and-platformio/</guid><description>
There are many different ways to develop and deploy embedded solutions, one of the most popular ones would be Arduino IDE. But the editor is very simplistic, without handy features such as intellisense, code refactoring and many others. I've used AVR Studio, IAR, even VIM to develop code for AVR/STM microcontrollers.. But they are either designed specifically for that platform or are commercial products. And I love Open Source :)</description></item><item><title>Python development with Visual Studio Code</title><link>https://itohi.com/blog/python-development-with-visual-studio-code/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Jul 2018 01:01:28 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://itohi.com/blog/python-development-with-visual-studio-code/</guid><description>
VS Code is an light but powerful editor developed by Microsoft. I have been using this editor for Python and embedded development(using PlatformIO) for a few months now.
Using PlatformIO with VSCode is rather simple - just install it through built in package manager and you're good to go. However python development needs a bit more work to setup properly. Especially if you want to develop Django apps with VSCode. That is what I'll be covering here in this post.</description></item><item><title>Building ESP-1 balancing robot</title><link>https://itohi.com/blog/building-esp-1-balancing-robot/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Jul 2018 01:01:28 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://itohi.com/blog/building-esp-1-balancing-robot/</guid><description>
I was always fascinated with balancing robots and wanted to build one myself. Some time ago I started collecting IMU, arduino boards, wheels, motors for other wheeled robots and one day decided to build a balancing robot instead. I've used wheels from old four wheel drive robot that used mouse sensors for odometry and was driven by an Arduino Pro mini. That robot never went alive anyway :)
Originally the robot was built using Arduino pro mini and all it could do was balance.</description></item><item><title>ESP8266 Wheelie</title><link>https://itohi.com/blog/esp8266-wheelie/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Jul 2018 01:01:28 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://itohi.com/blog/esp8266-wheelie/</guid><description>
As I've mentioned in the last blog post, I was trying to build a four wheel drive robot using arduino that utilizes two A3080 mouse sensors for odometry. Sadly that project never got finished and I disassembled the robot and built a balancing robot instead. However later I decided to not abandon the four wheel drive robot and ordered several ADNS3080 sensors with proper optics, obtained an electric wheelie toy, which lead to the birth of this WiFi controlled toy car.</description></item></channel></rss>