<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>tools on ITOHI</title><link>https://itohi.com/categories/tools/</link><description>Recent content in tools on ITOHI</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><copyright>2022 @ ITOHI - All rights reserved</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sat, 13 Jul 2019 17:44:47 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://itohi.com/categories/tools/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Esp8266 Driven Oven Controller Over Web Ui</title><link>https://itohi.com/esp-reflow/esp8266-driven-oven-controller-over-web-ui/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Jul 2019 17:44:47 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://itohi.com/esp-reflow/esp8266-driven-oven-controller-over-web-ui/</guid><description>
!!! WARNING: This project deals with mains power and high current !!! Please be careful if you wish to replicate any of its functionality and never work on a PCB or any open wires that are connected to the mains ! Author has no responsibility for your safety and wellbeing, so please take care of yourself.
How it works The purpose of this project is to control a heater of any sort to facilitate SMT reflow soldering utilizing a predefined temperature profile.</description></item><item><title>Arduino Metal Detector using frequency counter and OLED display</title><link>https://itohi.com/blog/metal-detector-using-frequency-counter-and-oled-display/</link><pubDate>Sun, 08 Jul 2018 01:01:28 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://itohi.com/blog/metal-detector-using-frequency-counter-and-oled-display/</guid><description>
There are a lot of forests in Lithuania which I like exploring on my bike. In the past a lot of Lithuanian resistance troops resided in those forests, so there is a big probability to stumble upon a stash of some kind. However that stash might as well be a grenade or a bomb of some kind, but nevertheless I always wanted to combine my motorcycle riding through the woods with treasure hunting and some time ago I decided to build a simple metal detector.</description></item></channel></rss>