<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>arduino on ITOHI</title><link>https://itohi.com/tags/arduino/</link><description>Recent content in arduino on ITOHI</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><copyright>2022 @ ITOHI - All rights reserved</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2019 01:01:28 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://itohi.com/tags/arduino/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Arduino ESP8266 Smart Motion Sensor using PIR and MQTT</title><link>https://itohi.com/blog/esp-1-smart-motion-sensor-using-pir-and-mqtt/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2019 01:01:28 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://itohi.com/blog/esp-1-smart-motion-sensor-using-pir-and-mqtt/</guid><description>
Motivation My son has a cat. And I've become very curious about the cat's feeding and toilet habits. Mainly I'm interested in how long does it take him to go to the toilet after eating as I've noticed a pattern: At first he goes to the kitchen, eats and then runs around the house wrecking havoc for some time and then goes to the toilet. So I'm curious whether this is his usual routine and moreover how many times during the day and night does he need to use his toilet.</description></item><item><title>Building ESP8266 Weather station with BME280 (part 2)</title><link>https://itohi.com/blog/building-esp8266-weather-station-part-ii/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2019 01:01:28 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://itohi.com/blog/building-esp8266-weather-station-part-ii/</guid><description>
In a previous post I've described how to build a Weather Station based on ESP8266 chip and various breakout boards you can buy e.g. on Aliexpress. In this post, however I'll share with you how I built a standalone PCB boards containing all the required components. To recap - this is a ESP8266 based Weather Station, that measures surrounding air temperature, humidity, pressure along with light and battery voltage. Connects to an MQTT broker and reports it's data there.</description></item><item><title>Arduino Metal Detector using frequency counter and OLED display</title><link>https://itohi.com/blog/metal-detector-using-frequency-counter-and-oled-display/</link><pubDate>Sun, 08 Jul 2018 01:01:28 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://itohi.com/blog/metal-detector-using-frequency-counter-and-oled-display/</guid><description>
There are a lot of forests in Lithuania which I like exploring on my bike. In the past a lot of Lithuanian resistance troops resided in those forests, so there is a big probability to stumble upon a stash of some kind. However that stash might as well be a grenade or a bomb of some kind, but nevertheless I always wanted to combine my motorcycle riding through the woods with treasure hunting and some time ago I decided to build a simple metal detector.</description></item><item><title>Building ESP8266 Weather station with BME280 (part 1)</title><link>https://itohi.com/blog/building-esp8266-weather-station-part-i/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Jul 2018 01:01:28 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://itohi.com/blog/building-esp8266-weather-station-part-i/</guid><description>
Ever since I started playing around with ESP modules I wanted to measure weather conditions in multiple location at home, friends, etc. The best way to achieve that would be to build a station that gathers various environment parameters and publishes them somewhere. That is what I've done. The very first prototype was done using ESP-1 module, DHT-11 humidity sensor and BMP280 breakout board. The station publishes gathered data to a MQTT broker from where it can be further gathered and analysed.</description></item><item><title>Building ESP-1 balancing robot</title><link>https://itohi.com/blog/building-esp-1-balancing-robot/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Jul 2018 01:01:28 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://itohi.com/blog/building-esp-1-balancing-robot/</guid><description>
I was always fascinated with balancing robots and wanted to build one myself. Some time ago I started collecting IMU, arduino boards, wheels, motors for other wheeled robots and one day decided to build a balancing robot instead. I've used wheels from old four wheel drive robot that used mouse sensors for odometry and was driven by an Arduino Pro mini. That robot never went alive anyway :)
Originally the robot was built using Arduino pro mini and all it could do was balance.</description></item><item><title>ESP8266 Wheelie</title><link>https://itohi.com/blog/esp8266-wheelie/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Jul 2018 01:01:28 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://itohi.com/blog/esp8266-wheelie/</guid><description>
As I've mentioned in the last blog post, I was trying to build a four wheel drive robot using arduino that utilizes two A3080 mouse sensors for odometry. Sadly that project never got finished and I disassembled the robot and built a balancing robot instead. However later I decided to not abandon the four wheel drive robot and ordered several ADNS3080 sensors with proper optics, obtained an electric wheelie toy, which lead to the birth of this WiFi controlled toy car.</description></item></channel></rss>